<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zen Life</title>
    <link>http://bbchen.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zen Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbchen&#34;&gt;Zen Life&lt;/a&gt; 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://bbchen.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to overcome procrastination?</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/12/how-to-overcome-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/12/how-to-overcome-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Everyone is the slave of procrastination. When a task is difficult, people are trying to avoid it. So people often procrastinate. That is, we will do the important ask unless we have to do it in the last minute. You can imagine how anxious and desperate you are when you find that the important task has not been finished and the deadline is just hours away. What we usually do is to scratch our heads and force us to finish it, as the price of not finishing the important task is extremely high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is true the more one procrastinates, the more anxiety one has. Procrastination could also diminish your productivity. People often find that procrastination is the worst enemy in work and life. One often asked question is &amp;ldquo;How I can overcome procrastination&amp;rdquo;. That is the question that I often ask myself and search online to find a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-i-overcome-the-habit-of-procrastination&#34;&gt;How can I overcome the habit of procrastination&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forget about rationale&lt;/strong&gt;
When you decide what to do in the next few hours, logics and rationale do not help. You probably have one dozen reasons that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to do the important tasks. Remember, you just have one thing to do for the next few hours. Try not to argue with yourself whether you want to do the task. Just do it and do nothing else. This is as simple as that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive attitude&lt;/strong&gt;
Nobody can be always positive about anything. Relax and tell yourself life is good and I love my work. Day dream the positive outcome if you finish your work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establish some disciplines and reward mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;
Establish discipline and reward policy. If you finish the work, you need to reward yourself by doing things you like, such as a relaxing walk, listening to your favorite music, and watching a short movie. Your task is in your task list, there will be some bad outcome if you can not finish it on time. Although you anxiety level will increase if you can not finish it, you also need to let yourself know clearly the importance of checking it off your list. Any negative feelings are much less important than your resistance of doing the task. Try to restrain yourself from the negative feelings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivate yourself&lt;/strong&gt;
When you feel your mode is low, set alarm and then listen to some music. Write motivational messages on the wall or on sticky notes in your computer. Whenever you find out that you are off the track, turn to these motivational messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start immediately on the task&lt;/strong&gt;
It is difficult to start. One always tries hard to avoid the difficult and somewhat boring work. Nowadays there are a lot of distractions. Formulate a routine that start immediately without arguing with yourself whether you need to start. When you write down a task in the list, you have already decided it is important and you have to do that first thing in the morning. Just start and do it, as simple as that. No one can be comfortable and productive at the same time. You choose this career, there must be something you truly love in your heart. What you are doing right now makes you one step closer to your dream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distraction-free work environment&lt;/strong&gt;
In the Internet age, there are many distractions from news media, tweeters, Facebook, online bbs. Your life is bombarded with lots of information, most of which are not useful. It is a hug time sink. The distraction and interruption will kill your valuable time for the work that can help realize your dream. When you start your session (e.g. 25 min pomodoro), do not turn on your cell phone, open web browser to surf the website, or respond to emails (emails are rarely emergent).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, &lt;strong&gt;be your life&amp;rsquo;s master, but slave.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am an Earth Scientist from Honolulu, Hawaii, USA. I am passionate about science, technology, art, literature, and nature. Through this platform, I am sharing my thoughts, ideas, tips, and cool stuff to you and other readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website is generated with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbchen/bbchen.github.io&#34;&gt;open sourced&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.  Articles are licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some of the applications, websites, and technologies that I use on a regular basis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com&#34;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; source code editor with a wide variety of plugins available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ia.net&#34;&gt;iAWriter&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; minimal but powerful markdown editor. I use it for my daily writings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; online Git-based project hosting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus&#34;&gt;Omnifocus&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; Mac application adopting the GTD productivity principals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zenhabits.net&#34;&gt;Zen Habits&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; Zen Habits is about finding simplicity and mindfulness in the daily chaos of our lives. It’s about clearing the clutter so we can focus on what’s important, create something amazing, find happiness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-details&#34;&gt;Other Details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com/bbchen&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/bbchen&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/in/bbchen&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Doing Now</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am an Earth scientists, focusing on deep Earth research. This page lists what I am currently doing for my life and research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io/book-list&#34;&gt;Book Reading List&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; list of books that I have read and am currently reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io/habits&#34;&gt;Habits&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; list of habits that I am currently sticking to, following the &lt;a href=&#34;http://zenhabits.net/&#34;&gt;Zen Habits&lt;/a&gt; principals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page was inspired by the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sivers.org/nowff&#34;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Updated: Dec 4, 2016&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habit 1, Become an Early Riser</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/habit-1-become-an-early-riser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/habit-1-become-an-early-riser/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-habit-become-an-early-riser&#34;&gt;New habit: Become an early riser&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I get up at about 7 am and sleep at midnight (12-1 am). In the month of January, I will sleep early and get up early. My final aim is to get up at 5 am in the morning, after 6-7 hours sleep. So I need to sleep before 11 pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To form this habit of &lt;strong&gt;rising at 5am&lt;/strong&gt;, I would like to break the habits into the following easy steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 1: Get up at 6:30 am, sleep early at 11:30 pm,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 2: Get up at 6:00 am, sleep early at 11:00 pm,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 3: Get up at 5:30 am,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 4: Get up at 5:00 am,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 5-6: Finally reinforce the new habit of &lt;em&gt;becoming an early riser&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the habit-forming steps, I hope I can get up at 5 am in the morning after enough sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I get up, I should start the morning routine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink a warm cup of water or tea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stretch or exercise, or meditate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the Inbox, and set the three most important tasks (MIT) for the day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start to work on the first MIT (mostly writing) right away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 1: Mostly get up at 7 am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 2: Mostly get up at 6 am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 3: Mostly get up at 5:30 am and start to work at 5:30 am.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book List</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/book-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/book-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is the list of the &lt;strong&gt;books&lt;/strong&gt; I am reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leo Babauta (2015) &lt;em&gt;Essential Zen Habits: Mastering the Art of Change, Briefly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert M. Hazen (2012) &lt;em&gt;The Story of Earth&lt;/em&gt;. 306pp.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habit</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Create a new habit every 5-6 weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year 2016&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January &amp;ndash; Be an early riser: Wake up at 5 am in the morning and follow the morning routine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;February &amp;ndash; Become a runner: Run 3 times a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection of 2015 and Plan for 2016</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/reflection-of-2015-and-plan-for-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/reflection-of-2015-and-plan-for-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year, I always would like to ask myself the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I have accomplished for the last year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I would like to accomplish for the new year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I did not quite do right in the past yar?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How I am going to accomplish more in the new year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I ask myself the above questions, I feel very guilty for what I haven&amp;rsquo;t done and what I could have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is called the new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution. A lot of people often perform reflection in the new year and set plans for the upcoming new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First thing first, what I have accomplished for the year of 2015&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Received positive news for my first NSF grant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taught my first course: Mineralogy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gave an invited talk at the AGU fall meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renovated my large volume press laboratory, now housing four big presses for pressurecooker-like work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I have not accomplished and what are under my own expectation in the year of 2015&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weak publication. I should have written more papers, rather than proposals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procrastination &amp;ndash; always wait for the last moment to finish my work, which actually made my life quite stressful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of motivation of exercising and becoming healthier. After I purchased the parking permit, I stopped biking to work. And my body weight significantly increased. My body mass index (BMI), for the first time, falls into the lower end of the overweight range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent little time with family, especially kids. Even at night, I worked in my office. However, the productivity is quite bad. In other words, the imbalance of life style really gave me hard time in focusing on my work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what is the new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution for myself?&lt;/strong&gt; In the year of 2016, I am planning to establish some good habits and overcome the bad habits one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more books, not only books in my research field, but some general topic books. Reading more good books makes one live wise. Read the books in the &lt;a href=&#34;{filename}/pages/book-list.md&#34;&gt;Book Reading List&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write routinely. Everyday, spend 30 minutes and write at least 700 words. Do not check how good the writing is. Just sit down and start to write. Remember, the &lt;em&gt;3R&lt;/em&gt; principals of effective writing: Revise, revise and revise. You can always have the opportunity to revise your articles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overcome (probably not that easy, but I will try my best) procrastination. Always set the deadline 2-3 days earlier and work towards the deadline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish a good habit every six weeks. See &lt;a href=&#34;{filename}/pages/habits.md&#34;&gt;Habit List&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run 3 times a week. This can be done in the morning or in the afternoon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And most importantly, what is the new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution for my family?&lt;/strong&gt; Family is what I value the most important part of one&amp;rsquo;s life. I am blessed that I have a nice family, with two little and lovely kids. In the new year, I am planning to accomplish the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read to kids every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give them a decent and memorable vacation to the family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more time with wife and kids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to cook nutritious and healthy breakfast for the family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be a role model for the kids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are always more things I would like to accomplish. Let me start from small things first, one after another. And I believe more will be accomplished by the end of the year. I am writing more reflections in this personal blogs to keep track of the changes I made and things I finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change will come; may you have the wisdom and courage to adapt &amp;ndash; Robert Hazen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe my life will become better if I start to change now on an incremental basis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Word</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/hello-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/hello-word/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change will come; may you have the wisdom and courage to adapt&lt;br /&gt;
— Robert Hazen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello World!&lt;/strong&gt; Aloha from Honolulu, Hawaii, USA. My screen name is bbchen. I lives in Honolulu, Hawaii with my wife and two little kids, where I write, read, and run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io&#34;&gt;Zen Life&lt;/a&gt;, a blog maintained by myself. I will post my thoughts, writings, and anything I found useful to this blog. If you would like to contact me, feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bbchen&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bbchen@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a note to myself in this &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hello World!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; message, I would like to form the following writing and reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io/habits&#34;&gt;habits&lt;/a&gt; in the new year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;: I am going to write on average one blog post (at least 700 words) every 2-3 weeks to record my life and keep myself on track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt;: I am going to read one book per month. See my &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io/book-list&#34;&gt;Book Reading List&lt;/a&gt;, which will be updated routinely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find anything useful in my website, feel free to share them. All the content in my website is uncopyrighted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best way to reach me is by Email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bbchen@gmail.com&#34;&gt;bbchen@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stack</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/colophon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This site is a DIY project to put in practice what I learn in my web development education journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidwalsh.name/introduction-static-site-generators&#34;&gt;static site generator&lt;/a&gt; made with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.golang.org&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo takes content written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; and blends it with a set of templates that combine HTML and Go code, producing a static site that I then deploy to the public web via &lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For layout and styling, I am using a responsive framework called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getskeleton.com&#34;&gt;Skeleton&lt;/a&gt;, together with a &lt;a href=&#34;../../css/style.css&#34;&gt;custom style sheet&lt;/a&gt; to style some HTML elements, classes and IDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep track of changes to my site with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.git-scm.com&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, and store my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mariobox/mariosanchez.org&#34;&gt;source files&lt;/a&gt; in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; remote repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do most of my work from the command line, on a Linux terminal emulator called Git Bash that comes with &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;Git for Windows&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For coding, I use either &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com&#34;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/archives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I write whenever I can. This is a place where I log my ideas, notes, and thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>