<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zen Life</title>
    <link>http://bbchen.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zen Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbchen&#34;&gt;Zen Life&lt;/a&gt; 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://bbchen.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>我怎么克服我的拖延症？</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/12/%E6%88%91%E6%80%8E%E4%B9%88%E5%85%8B%E6%9C%8D%E6%88%91%E7%9A%84%E6%8B%96%E5%BB%B6%E7%97%87/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/12/%E6%88%91%E6%80%8E%E4%B9%88%E5%85%8B%E6%9C%8D%E6%88%91%E7%9A%84%E6%8B%96%E5%BB%B6%E7%97%87/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;其实写这种关于拖延症的文章太多， 方法理论数不胜数。 基本上很多都是打鸡血的高能正能量，看过一遍，能够坚持一阵子，没法在脑中留下太多印象。 然后过几天就又回到原来的样子， deadline前一天写assignment。 刚开始做正事就玩玩手机，刷刷微博， 逛逛人人。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;前几天在网上看到一篇关于拖延症的文章，其实不算文章，只是类似于国内知乎一样的网站上， 某个人提出了这样一个问题： 我怎么克服我的拖延症？ 其中的这个回答被like了9000多次，所以这个答案有没有用，不言自明。个人如此严重的拖延症觉得还是有指导意义的。
以下是原地址：&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.zhihu.com/?target=http%3A//www.quora.com/Life-Advice/How-do-I-get-over-my-bad-habit-of-procrastinating/answer/Oliver-Emberton&#34;&gt;Oliver Emberton&amp;rsquo;s answer to Procrastination: How do I get over my bad habit of procrastinating?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我只是当个搬运工 可以直接跳去看英文原版 我这个翻译实在是 班门弄斧 不得原意之处 各位海涵&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我怎么克服我拖延症的坏习惯？
首先我需要用两分钟利用一张漫画蛇来解释一下人类文明基本运作方式。（这里也可以理解是大脑的运作方式）&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;人都喜欢相信自己是很聪明的。 我们宁愿相信那些能让我们分离原子，登陆月球的伟大如爱因斯坦的大脑和那些甚至没法开始做一个第二天就要截止的作业的大脑是一样的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;人类从原始的生命进化而来， 但是人类从来都没有完全摆脱来自祖先原始低级生命的一些残留基因。 我们知道， 智慧的，理性部分的大脑我们称之为人为意识。我们暂且叫他Albert，他和另一个冲动的小爬虫一起住在你的大脑中， 这个爬虫我们就叫 Rex吧。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rex 是你的基础神经末节， 但是名字太麻烦， 所以我们还是叫Rex好了。
Rex是由几百万年前进化而来的（可以想象是有多原始），然而就是你脑子里的这个小爬虫（听起来有点瘆人）的直觉引导和激励你走到今天这一步。你所有的饥饿，恐惧， 爱，欲望都来自Rex。 Rex的思想是简单而原始的， 并且是非语言化的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;下面要说的这点你将不会喜欢： Rex拥有你作出的所有选择的决定权，对， 他决定你做的每一件事的选择！&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我们喜欢把Albert认为是我们的“真我”——也就是大脑的意识部分。他是那个说话和讲道理的部分。当我们决定去健身或者写那个几千字的学期作业，这是由 Albert 做这个决定。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;但是Rex并不一定听Albert的话。 就像一个小孩一样，只要他愿意， 他就会去做被指定做的事。但是一旦Rex更喜欢躺在沙发上吃着奇多再看几集 生活大爆炸， 那么这就是你接下来实际做的事。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;（这么听起来，好像我们就不会做正事了）不过，像我们身边的人一样要想完成那些不可思议的成就也是可能的， 因为我们发展了一个系统来安抚，抑制 我们大脑中的Rex。 而这个系统我们大多称之为“文明”。 食物和住所， 法律系统，正义 公正，义务制教育，娱乐消遣， 一夫一妻制等等。 所有的这些都能让Rex有足够长的时间安静下来， 而让脑中的Albert可以做些有用的事——比如发现青霉素或者发明奇多。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;好了现在我们来看看拖延症。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;当你在做每个决定的时候都是神志清醒的， 但是你却在奇怪为什么你没有去实行这些决定。原因就是真正决定你选择的控制权在Rex手中。——那个心志一点也不成熟的小爬虫。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;想象一下你需要一直说服一个小孩去做你想要他做的事，简单点做的话，宣示权威就行了， 比如说“该吃饭了” 但是如果是小孩不想做的事， 他就不会听你的。你就需要用甜言蜜语来哄他。所以你需要：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;忘记逻辑&lt;/strong&gt;
一旦你决定做任何事， 逻辑和理性对你没有任何帮助。你脑中的Rex可以被安抚，可以被满足， 可以被恐吓或者激励。 但是它是非语言化的， 是不能跟它讲道理的。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;对Rex适时的安慰很重要&lt;/strong&gt;
如果你饿了，累了或者情绪压抑了， Rex就会起兵造反。 一旦你没能照顾好你自己的各种需求（来自Rex）， 他就会尖叫哀嚎各种胡闹，就是不做你要他做的事。因为它存在的目的就是尽可能的吃， 睡，花时间玩。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;培养一些纪律约束自己&lt;/strong&gt;
建立一个奖惩分明的制度。 如果你要小孩子吃蔬菜，就先要把点心藏在最后一道上。完成一项任务就奖励自己，如果失败了也要按照既定的规则惩罚自己。有一些典型的例子， 比如致力于一个公共的目标， 或者和一个团队合作，社交压力也可以影响Rex。——抑制它，进而有效的做更多有用的事&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;刺激情绪&lt;/strong&gt;
你的Rex会对情绪做反应。这就是它的“语言”。 所以给自己打起鸡血来，或者吓吓自己，看看励志演讲或者文章可以帮助你刺激情绪，不过这效果只会持续一阵子。或者听一些令人振奋的音乐。一些激励人成功的图片或者失败后将会发生的后果， 让这些画面都生动到想想都激动或者害怕——也就达到刺激情绪的效果了。其实我们对小孩也是用的同样的方法： 要记得刷牙哦 不然它们都会掉下来！&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;强迫自己去做一个开头&lt;/strong&gt;
万事开头难，大部分Rex的意识和直觉就是逃避改变。 所以只要你开始了某件事，它的这些意识和直觉就会开始向有利于你的方向发展， 通过足够的时间，你甚至可以说服Rex喜欢上他讨厌做的事。 这就是我们强迫小孩上学或者学钢琴的原因。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;清理工作环境的视野&lt;/strong&gt;
Rex是一个近视眼， 而且很不聪明， 如果它看到一个微博网页， 他会想去看看， 这就像是在睡觉前给小孩看一段精彩的电视节目。—— 那他今晚就会折腾着不睡觉了。所以你要将你身边的环境变得没有这么分散注意力。 关了网页， 断了网， 手机静音， 有一个和消遣娱乐完全隔离的工作环境。（ 如果可以，尽量用不同的电脑工作和娱乐，或者至少用一个专门的工作账户登录电脑）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;所以综上，一旦你知道自己要做什么，你就会开始认知其中的规律，并且慢慢的控制那个小小的Rex。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在你的脑中住着一个毫不讲理并且冲动的小爬虫Rex，更不幸的是它还控制着你日常生活的方向盘。不过， 如果你可以很好的教育它呢， 它就会去做大部分你要它做的事，并且表现的很好。 只要你随时记得对自己说我的地盘我做主。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am an Earth Scientist from Honolulu, Hawaii, USA. I am passionate about science, technology, art, literature, and nature. Through this platform, I am sharing my thoughts, ideas, tips, and cool stuff to you and other readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website is generated with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbchen/bbchen.github.io&#34;&gt;open sourced&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.  Articles are licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some of the applications, websites, and technologies that I use on a regular basis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com&#34;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; source code editor with a wide variety of plugins available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ia.net&#34;&gt;iAWriter&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; minimal but powerful markdown editor. I use it for my daily writings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; online Git-based project hosting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus&#34;&gt;Omnifocus&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; Mac application adopting the GTD productivity principals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zenhabits.net&#34;&gt;Zen Habits&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; Zen Habits is about finding simplicity and mindfulness in the daily chaos of our lives. It’s about clearing the clutter so we can focus on what’s important, create something amazing, find happiness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-details&#34;&gt;Other Details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com/bbchen&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/bbchen&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/in/bbchen&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Doing Now</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am an Earth scientists, focusing on deep Earth research. This page lists what I am currently doing for my life and research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io/book-list&#34;&gt;Book Reading List&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; list of books that I have read and am currently reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io/habits&#34;&gt;Habits&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; list of habits that I am currently sticking to, following the &lt;a href=&#34;http://zenhabits.net/&#34;&gt;Zen Habits&lt;/a&gt; principals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page was inspired by the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sivers.org/nowff&#34;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Updated: Dec 4, 2016&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habit 1, Become an Early Riser</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/habit-1-become-an-early-riser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/habit-1-become-an-early-riser/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-habit-become-an-early-riser&#34;&gt;New habit: Become an early riser&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I get up at about 7 am and sleep at midnight (12-1 am). In the month of January, I will sleep early and get up early. My final aim is to get up at 5 am in the morning, after 6-7 hours sleep. So I need to sleep before 11 pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To form this habit of &lt;strong&gt;rising at 5am&lt;/strong&gt;, I would like to break the habits into the following easy steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 1: Get up at 6:30 am, sleep early at 11:30 pm,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 2: Get up at 6:00 am, sleep early at 11:00 pm,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 3: Get up at 5:30 am,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 4: Get up at 5:00 am,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 5-6: Finally reinforce the new habit of &lt;em&gt;becoming an early riser&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the habit-forming steps, I hope I can get up at 5 am in the morning after enough sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I get up, I should start the morning routine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink a warm cup of water or tea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stretch or exercise, or meditate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the Inbox, and set the three most important tasks (MIT) for the day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start to work on the first MIT (mostly writing) right away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 1: Mostly get up at 7 am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 2: Mostly get up at 6 am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 3: Mostly get up at 5:30 am and start to work at 5:30 am.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book List</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/book-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/book-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is the list of the &lt;strong&gt;books&lt;/strong&gt; I am reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leo Babauta (2015) &lt;em&gt;Essential Zen Habits: Mastering the Art of Change, Briefly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert M. Hazen (2012) &lt;em&gt;The Story of Earth&lt;/em&gt;. 306pp.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habit</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Create a new habit every 5-6 weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year 2016&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January &amp;ndash; Be an early riser: Wake up at 5 am in the morning and follow the morning routine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;February &amp;ndash; Become a runner: Run 3 times a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection of 2015 and Plan for 2016</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/reflection-of-2015-and-plan-for-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/reflection-of-2015-and-plan-for-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year, I always would like to ask myself the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I have accomplished for the last year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I would like to accomplish for the new year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I did not quite do right in the past yar?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How I am going to accomplish more in the new year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I ask myself the above questions, I feel very guilty for what I haven&amp;rsquo;t done and what I could have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is called the new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution. A lot of people often perform reflection in the new year and set plans for the upcoming new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First thing first, what I have accomplished for the year of 2015&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Received positive news for my first NSF grant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taught my first course: Mineralogy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gave an invited talk at the AGU fall meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renovated my large volume press laboratory, now housing four big presses for pressurecooker-like work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I have not accomplished and what are under my own expectation in the year of 2015&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weak publication. I should have written more papers, rather than proposals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procrastination &amp;ndash; always wait for the last moment to finish my work, which actually made my life quite stressful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of motivation of exercising and becoming healthier. After I purchased the parking permit, I stopped biking to work. And my body weight significantly increased. My body mass index (BMI), for the first time, falls into the lower end of the overweight range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent little time with family, especially kids. Even at night, I worked in my office. However, the productivity is quite bad. In other words, the imbalance of life style really gave me hard time in focusing on my work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what is the new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution for myself?&lt;/strong&gt; In the year of 2016, I am planning to establish some good habits and overcome the bad habits one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more books, not only books in my research field, but some general topic books. Reading more good books makes one live wise. Read the books in the &lt;a href=&#34;{filename}/pages/book-list.md&#34;&gt;Book Reading List&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write routinely. Everyday, spend 30 minutes and write at least 700 words. Do not check how good the writing is. Just sit down and start to write. Remember, the &lt;em&gt;3R&lt;/em&gt; principals of effective writing: Revise, revise and revise. You can always have the opportunity to revise your articles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overcome (probably not that easy, but I will try my best) procrastination. Always set the deadline 2-3 days earlier and work towards the deadline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish a good habit every six weeks. See &lt;a href=&#34;{filename}/pages/habits.md&#34;&gt;Habit List&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run 3 times a week. This can be done in the morning or in the afternoon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And most importantly, what is the new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution for my family?&lt;/strong&gt; Family is what I value the most important part of one&amp;rsquo;s life. I am blessed that I have a nice family, with two little and lovely kids. In the new year, I am planning to accomplish the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read to kids every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give them a decent and memorable vacation to the family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more time with wife and kids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to cook nutritious and healthy breakfast for the family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be a role model for the kids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are always more things I would like to accomplish. Let me start from small things first, one after another. And I believe more will be accomplished by the end of the year. I am writing more reflections in this personal blogs to keep track of the changes I made and things I finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change will come; may you have the wisdom and courage to adapt &amp;ndash; Robert Hazen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe my life will become better if I start to change now on an incremental basis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Word</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/hello-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/hello-word/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change will come; may you have the wisdom and courage to adapt&lt;br /&gt;
— Robert Hazen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello World!&lt;/strong&gt; Aloha from Honolulu, Hawaii, USA. My screen name is bbchen. I lives in Honolulu, Hawaii with my wife and two little kids, where I write, read, and run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io&#34;&gt;Zen Life&lt;/a&gt;, a blog maintained by myself. I will post my thoughts, writings, and anything I found useful to this blog. If you would like to contact me, feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bbchen&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bbchen@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a note to myself in this &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hello World!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; message, I would like to form the following writing and reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io/habits&#34;&gt;habits&lt;/a&gt; in the new year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;: I am going to write on average one blog post (at least 700 words) every 2-3 weeks to record my life and keep myself on track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt;: I am going to read one book per month. See my &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io/book-list&#34;&gt;Book Reading List&lt;/a&gt;, which will be updated routinely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find anything useful in my website, feel free to share them. All the content in my website is uncopyrighted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best way to reach me is by Email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bbchen@gmail.com&#34;&gt;bbchen@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stack</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/colophon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This site is a DIY project to put in practice what I learn in my web development education journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidwalsh.name/introduction-static-site-generators&#34;&gt;static site generator&lt;/a&gt; made with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.golang.org&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo takes content written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; and blends it with a set of templates that combine HTML and Go code, producing a static site that I then deploy to the public web via &lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For layout and styling, I am using a responsive framework called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getskeleton.com&#34;&gt;Skeleton&lt;/a&gt;, together with a &lt;a href=&#34;../../css/style.css&#34;&gt;custom style sheet&lt;/a&gt; to style some HTML elements, classes and IDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep track of changes to my site with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.git-scm.com&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, and store my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mariobox/mariosanchez.org&#34;&gt;source files&lt;/a&gt; in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; remote repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do most of my work from the command line, on a Linux terminal emulator called Git Bash that comes with &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;Git for Windows&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For coding, I use either &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com&#34;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/archives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I write whenever I can. This is a place where I log my ideas, notes, and thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>