<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on Zen Life</title>
    <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on Zen Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbchen&#34;&gt;Zen Life&lt;/a&gt; 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://bbchen.github.io/post.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Habit 1, Become an Early Riser</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/habit-1-become-an-early-riser.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/habit-1-become-an-early-riser.html</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-habit-become-an-early-riser&#34;&gt;New habit: Become an early riser&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I get up at about 7 am and sleep at midnight (12-1 am). In the month of January, I will sleep early and get up early. My final aim is to get up at 5 am in the morning, after 6-7 hours sleep. So I need to sleep before 11 pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To form this habit of &lt;strong&gt;rising at 5am&lt;/strong&gt;, I would like to break the habits into the following easy steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 1: Get up at 6:30 am, sleep early at 11:30 pm,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 2: Get up at 6:00 am, sleep early at 11:00 pm,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 3: Get up at 5:30 am,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 4: Get up at 5:00 am,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 5-6: Finally reinforce the new habit of &lt;em&gt;becoming an early riser&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the habit-forming steps, I hope I can get up at 5 am in the morning after enough sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I get up, I should start the morning routine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink a warm cup of water or tea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stretch or exercise, or meditate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the Inbox, and set the three most important tasks (MIT) for the day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start to work on the first MIT (mostly writing) right away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 1: Mostly get up at 7 am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 2: Mostly get up at 6 am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 3: Mostly get up at 5:30 am and start to work at 5:30 am.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection of 2015 and Plan for 2016</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/reflection-of-2015-and-plan-for-2016.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/reflection-of-2015-and-plan-for-2016.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year, I always would like to ask myself the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I have accomplished for the last year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I would like to accomplish for the new year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I did not quite do right in the past yar?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How I am going to accomplish more in the new year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I ask myself the above questions, I feel very guilty for what I haven&amp;rsquo;t done and what I could have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is called the new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution. A lot of people often perform reflection in the new year and set plans for the upcoming new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First thing first, what I have accomplished for the year of 2015&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Received positive news for my first NSF grant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taught my first course: Mineralogy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gave an invited talk at the AGU fall meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renovated my large volume press laboratory, now housing four big presses for pressurecooker-like work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I have not accomplished and what are under my own expectation in the year of 2015&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weak publication. I should have written more papers, rather than proposals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procrastination &amp;ndash; always wait for the last moment to finish my work, which actually made my life quite stressful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of motivation of exercising and becoming healthier. After I purchased the parking permit, I stopped biking to work. And my body weight significantly increased. My body mass index (BMI), for the first time, falls into the lower end of the overweight range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent little time with family, especially kids. Even at night, I worked in my office. However, the productivity is quite bad. In other words, the imbalance of life style really gave me hard time in focusing on my work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what is the new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution for myself?&lt;/strong&gt; In the year of 2016, I am planning to establish some good habits and overcome the bad habits one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more books, not only books in my research field, but some general topic books. Reading more good books makes one live wise. Read the books in the &lt;a href=&#34;{filename}/pages/book-list.md&#34;&gt;Book Reading List&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write routinely. Everyday, spend 30 minutes and write at least 700 words. Do not check how good the writing is. Just sit down and start to write. Remember, the &lt;em&gt;3R&lt;/em&gt; principals of effective writing: Revise, revise and revise. You can always have the opportunity to revise your articles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overcome (probably not that easy, but I will try my best) procrastination. Always set the deadline 2-3 days earlier and work towards the deadline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish a good habit every six weeks. See &lt;a href=&#34;{filename}/pages/habits.md&#34;&gt;Habit List&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run 3 times a week. This can be done in the morning or in the afternoon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And most importantly, what is the new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution for my family?&lt;/strong&gt; Family is what I value the most important part of one&amp;rsquo;s life. I am blessed that I have a nice family, with two little and lovely kids. In the new year, I am planning to accomplish the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read to kids every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give them a decent and memorable vacation to the family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend more time with wife and kids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to cook nutritious and healthy breakfast for the family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be a role model for the kids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are always more things I would like to accomplish. Let me start from small things first, one after another. And I believe more will be accomplished by the end of the year. I am writing more reflections in this personal blogs to keep track of the changes I made and things I finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change will come; may you have the wisdom and courage to adapt &amp;ndash; Robert Hazen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe my life will become better if I start to change now on an incremental basis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Word</title>
      <link>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/hello-word.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bbchen.github.io/post/2016/01/hello-word.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change will come; may you have the wisdom and courage to adapt&lt;br /&gt;
— Robert Hazen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello World!&lt;/strong&gt; Aloha from Honolulu, Hawaii, USA. My screen name is bbchen. I lives in Honolulu, Hawaii with my wife and two little kids, where I write, read, and run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io&#34;&gt;Zen Life&lt;/a&gt;, a blog maintained by myself. I will post my thoughts, writings, and anything I found useful to this blog. If you would like to contact me, feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bbchen&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bbchen@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a note to myself in this &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hello World!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; message, I would like to form the following writing and reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io/habits&#34;&gt;habits&lt;/a&gt; in the new year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;: I am going to write on average one blog post (at least 700 words) every 2-3 weeks to record my life and keep myself on track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt;: I am going to read one book per month. See my &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbchen.github.io/book-list&#34;&gt;Book Reading List&lt;/a&gt;, which will be updated routinely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find anything useful in my website, feel free to share them. All the content in my website is uncopyrighted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>